About

Data Engineer-II and Ex.Data Scientist with 3+ years of experience in Designing and Implementing ML Models, ETL pipelines, Data Mesh and Analytics. Possess PGD in Big Data Analytics from CDAC ACTS (HQ), Pune. Seeking to leverage my Mathematical knowledge, Analytics abilities, and ML models development competency in the role of Data Analytics.

EDUCATION

CDAC -PGD Big Data Analytics
Pune
Maharashtra
2018 – 2019

B.Tech. ECE Rajasthan Technical University Jaipur, RJ 2010 – 2014

SKILLS

Machine Learning

Reinforcement Learning, GAN
Python, Java, R
Big Data, Spark, Hive, Kafka
SQL (DBMS)
Mathematics (Statistics, Calculus)
Pytorch, TensorFlow

Contact

6

(+91) 8239-3838-47



rsohlot@gmail.com



Bangalore, IN



linkedin.com/in/rsohlot

https://rsohlot.github.io

CERTIFICATION

Market Analysis Course (Jan 2017 – March 2017)

Machine Learning, Coursera (May 2016- June 2017)

Spark Working (Dec 2019)

GAN with Pytorch (May 2020 – June 2020)

Al Workflow: Feature Engineering and Bias Detection (July 2020 – July 2020)

Professional experience

2020 - Present

Data Engineer-II, Infinx HealthCare, Bangalore

- IRIS: An embedded quick sight dashboard to help client analyzing their revenue. Build a generalized ETL pipeline to make easier onboard for newer client implementation.
- IROS: Designing and implementing the Product to prioritize A/R Inventory to maximize the revenue recovery, using tree-based ML models. Product is backed by spark ETL pipeline running on AWS environment using following services: Airflow, EMR, redshift, postgres, glue, Athena, S3, pyspark, Quicksight
- Transforming (containing 80 col derivation) 70 Lakh record in 5 min. (EMR + pyspark)

2019 - 2020

Associate Data Scientist, KratinLLC, Nagpur

- Designed a Time Series Model give accuracy up to 97% used to create an AI smart SAP tool to maximize the workforce utilization considering all the preferences and requirements. Results in saving the 500 miles every week of the workforce traveling.
- Estimated the future demand to get the best assignment of workforce. Tools used prophet, optaplanner, Django, plotly, pandas, docker.
- Designed and implemented the warehouse for the BI and analytics. Saved daily 1 hr. task of the team to fetch, validate and store the data. This was done with Hadoop, hive, spark, hue, Apache Atlus, Apache ranger.

Co-Founder, WHT, Bhiwadi, RJ

Founded WHT. It was a Logistics Firm. Learnt the Logistics business flow of Northern India. Firm manages complete workflow of goods for the various Industries.

Personal Projects

Open-Source Contribution

Chaos-genius (github)

- Design and discussion in adding new KPIs related to data metrics.
- Adding new features to product.